# TIMOTHY YI

Orange County, CA | 949-861-0419 | timothy.yi7@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Strong: React.js, Redux, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, GitHub, Google Dev Tools, Slack

**Experienced:** PHP, Node.js, OOP, API's, AJAX, Firebase, AWS, Postman

#### **APPLICATIONS DEVELOPED**

Batsu! Live | GitHub

An accountability application that helps people keep others accountable for events

 Utilized React.js and Redux to create components that worked in unison with PHP and MySQL to create the functionality and logic of the application. Utilized CSS3 to apply styling and animations

Othello Live | GitHub

A Star Wars Jedi vs. Sith themed Othello (reversi) application

Utilized HTML5 for the basic skeleton of the application, CSS3 to apply the styling and animations, and
JavaScript, jQuery, and OOP to create the logic and functionality

Memory Match Live | GitHub

• A Star Wars themed memory match application that tracks accuracy, guesses, and statistics

 Utilized HTML5 to create the basic skeleton, CSS3 to apply styling and animations, and JavaScript, jQuery, and DOM creation/manipulation to create the logic, functionality, and statistics

Daily Report Live | GitHub

• An application designed to locate a destination, give the weather, as well as the average traffic rate

 Utilized HTML5 to create the basic skeleton, CSS3 to apply styling and animations, and JavaScript, jQuery, and DOM creation/manipulation to create the logic, functionality, and statistics. Utilized Google Maps and Weather Underground API integration using AJAX calls.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Kaplan International Colleges - English Instructor

*Irvine, CA* (2012-2013, 2013-2017)

- Worked as a teacher to assist students (15 students/class), from various countries, enter US universities/colleges
- Performed a variety of IT and technical assistance throughout the school due to a lack of IT support from the company

### **AEON Japan** - English Instructor

*Tokyo, Japan* (2013)

- Utilized technology in classes (10-15 students/class; iOS/iPad integration) of all ages to improve language acquisition.
- Met with staff and students in weekly scheduled meetings to create work plans that best suited each student's needs

# C2 Korea - English Instructor / R&D coordinator

Bundang, South Korea (2009-2011)

- Worked as an English teacher for students (10-15 students/class), to improve their English acquisition skills
- Created curriculum and materials to help improve school and student quality through technology-based learning

# **EDUCATION EXPERIENCE**

# **LearningFuze** - Front-End Development

Irvine, CA (2017)

Accelerated Web Development Program - 12 weeks

# **Udemy** - Front-End Development

*Irvine, CA* (2017)

Online Courses: React with Redux, ES6, JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS3, Bootstrap4, Full-Stack Development

# **UC Irvine Extension** – TEFL Certification

*Irvine, CA* (2009-2009)

Teaching English as a Foreign Language Course – 200 hours

### **UC Riverside** - BA in Economics Administration

*Riverside, CA* (2004-2009)

Concentration in Business Marketing

### **PERSONAL INTERESTS**

I am an avid soccer fan who has played in the past, and follow a variety of teams. I have a strong interest in motorsports and enjoy driving. I have a strong interest in technology and strive to know the ins-and-outs of current trends and recent updates. With that said, I am also an avid gamer who plays games such as Destiny, Final Fantasy, and a variety of others. During my free time, I enjoy traveling, camping, and backpacking throughout the country.